That man also knows...
그 사람도 알아요...
Are you going to marry a septuagenarian?
70대 노인과 결혼할 건가요?
Your expression is getting more and more interesting the more I look at it
네 표정은 볼수록 재밌어
If that kid knew, it would be more interesting
그 아이가 알면 더 재미있을 텐데
Hello
안녕하세요
Say it yourself
직접 말해보세요
I am...who?
나는...누구?
Didn't you say you were an uninvited guest?
초대받지 않은 손님이라고 하지 않았나요?
Then let's take it for granted.
그럼 당연하게 여기자.
This…
이…
Just the man I'm attracted to
그냥 내가 끌리는 남자야
And we are getting married soon
그리고 우리 곧 결혼해요
By the way, this is an officer from the Bureau of Robbery.
그건 그렇고, 이것은 강도 국의 장교입니다.
As for the name…
이름은…
pleasure
즐거움
this is my name
이게 내 이름이야
If it goes as you said
말씀대로 된다면
I have no interest in sharing my first name with you right now.
나는 지금 당장 당신과 내 이름을 공유하고 싶지 않습니다.
So that’s it for introducing each other.
그럼 서로 소개는 끝났습니다.
It's dark. I don't know why you came here.
어둡습니다. 당신이 여기에 왜 왔는지 모르겠어요.
Just think of it as disciplining the family.
가족을 징계하는 것이라고 생각해보세요.
Hello Eunjo
안녕하세요 은조님
Did you come here with my young master?
내 젊은 스승님과 함께 여기에 오셨나요?
young master
젊은 주인
How much wine did you drink?
와인을 얼마나 마셨나요?
What's going on with the blood on your face?
얼굴에 피가 흐르고 있는데 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
are you injured
당신은 부상을 입었습니까?
You stand up first
먼저 일어서세요
Has Zai Yi left?
자이가 떠났나요?
future in-laws
미래의 친척
Okay…
알았어…
You stand up first
먼저 일어서세요
When will that guy Enzu come over?
그 엔즈씨는 언제 오나요?
Didn't you say you'd come over after your shift?
퇴근하고 오겠다고 하지 않았나요?
Are you delaying treatment because you are helping someone again?
또 누군가를 도우려고 치료를 미루고 계시나요?
Yes
예
How can such a good life be without my benefactor?
나의 은인 없이 어떻게 그렇게 좋은 삶을 살 수 있습니까?
That's right
그렇죠
Start with me
나부터 시작하세요
Is there anyone here who has not received help from Eunjo?
여기 은조의 도움을 받지 못한 사람이 있나요?
That's right, that's right
그렇죠, 그렇죠
no one
아무도
Come on…
어서…
Who is Eunjo?
은조는 누구인가?
She
그녀
It's that Dr. Hong who works at the Huimin Office.
희민사업소에서 근무하시는 홍박사님이십니다.
Welfare Department
복지부
My adults should be there too.
어른들도 거기 있어야 해요.
Hello
안녕하세요
The word "discipline"
"징계"라는 단어
It's a word that people like me, who are law-abiding, would use.
저처럼 법을 준수하는 사람들이 쓰는 단어죠.
Is this what you should say to a woman who is about to get married?
결혼을 앞둔 여자에게 이런 말을 해야 할까요?
I'm not talking about her
나는 그녀에 대해 말하는 것이 아닙니다
What I am controlling is the way you, the officer, look at her.
내가 통제하고 있는 것은 경찰관인 당신이 그녀를 보는 방식입니다.
Then you can see it quite clearly
그러면 아주 명확하게 알 수 있죠
unfortunately
불행하게도
She has just drawn an insurmountable line for me
그녀는 나에게 넘을 수 없는 선을 그어버렸어요
In other words
즉,
She has always been well-behaved and has never had to be disciplined.
그녀는 항상 품행이 바르고 징계를 받은 적이 없습니다.
This will not be possible in the future
앞으로는 이런 일이 없을 것이다
As a future husband, you should at least know this
미래의 남편이라면 이것만은 알아야 할 것 같아요.
When are you going to punch?
언제 펀칭할 예정인가요?
It looks like he's about to punch. I'd better get out of the way first.
곧 펀치를 날릴 것 같습니다. 내가 먼저 비켜가는 게 낫겠다.
I've always been more mature
난 항상 더 성숙해졌어
It’s no longer the age to shake fists at every turn
더 이상 돌 때마다 주먹을 휘둘러야 할 시대가 아니다
Besides, in my capacity
게다가 내 능력으로는
Mostly swords are used
검을 주로 사용함
If you want to make things easier, I can also give you poisonous wine directly.
일을 쉽게 하고 싶다면 독주를 직접 드릴 수도 있습니다.
It's scary. Should I be scared?
무섭다. 무서워해야합니까?
if necessary
필요한 경우
Why are so many people in the world attracted to these women?
왜 세계의 많은 사람들이 이 여성들에게 매력을 느끼는 걸까요?
What you said has been very unpleasant since just now.
당신이 말한 것은 지금부터 매우 불쾌했습니다.
because that's the truth
그게 진실이니까
That girl was just sold to our house
그 여자가 방금 우리 집에 팔렸어요
She can only be regarded as a concubine at best...
그녀는 기껏해야 첩으로 간주 될 수 있습니다 ...
I really can't listen anymore
정말 이제 더 이상 들을 수가 없어요
I treated you politely just now because you are the person Hong Enzu is going to marry.
지금은 홍엔즈가 결혼할 사람이니까 정중하게 대해줬어요.
what are you doing
뭐하는거야?
what is this doing
이게 뭐하는 거야?
get out of the way
길을 비켜라
why do this
왜 이런 짓을 해?
How interesting
얼마나 흥미로운가
Please go back
돌아가주세요
Thank you for your help during this time
그동안 도와주셔서 감사합니다
From now on we won't meet again
이제부터 우리는 다시는 만나지 않을 거예요
Eunjo Hong Eunjo
홍은조
Enzu
엔즈
What's going on with this triangular confrontation?
이 삼각대결은 어떻게 되는 걸까요?
This atmosphere…
이 분위기는…
We should get to know each other and leave, right?
우리 서로 좀 알아보고 떠나야겠죠?
Everyone just took ten steps back
모두가 열 걸음 뒤로 물러났어요
one two three…
하나 둘 셋…
I'm here too
나도 여기 있어
I knew you were here
나는 당신이 여기 있다는 것을 알았습니다
As long as you know, come here
알면 여기로 와
What's wrong? Isn't the person there?
무슨 일이야? 그 사람은 거기 없나요?
wait a moment
잠깐만요
I will go back with you as an officer.
나는 장교로서 당신과 함께 돌아갈 것입니다.
That's what I meant
그게 내 뜻이야
Go ahead and ask
가서 물어보세요
Aren't you the right-hand man of the great king?
너는 큰 왕의 오른팔이 아니냐?
Aren't you also the confidant of the great king?
너도 대왕의 신복이 아니냐?
Sir
선생님
What happened between you and Dr. Hong?
당신과 홍 박사 사이에 무슨 일이 있었나요?
Sir…
선생님…
I apologize to you on his behalf for what happened just now.
방금 일어난 일에 대해 그를 대신하여 사과드립니다.
Looks like I'm not an uninvited guest
초대받지 않은 손님은 아닌 것 같은데
Instead, I helped you.
대신 내가 도와줬어요.
It actually has both
실제로는 둘 다 있습니다.
Then your expression should be happier, right?
그럼 표정이 좀 더 행복해졌겠죠?
At least I helped you keep it
적어도 나는 당신이 그것을 유지하도록 도왔습니다
The last self-esteem you don’t want to be seen through by a man who likes you
좋아하는 남자에게 들키고 싶지 않은 마지막 자존심
So they were so happy
그래서 그들은 너무 행복했어요
live for a long time
오래오래 살아라
Even as a wicked girl
사악한 여자라도
Maybe I’d also imagine being remembered like this.
어쩌면 나 또한 이렇게 기억되는 것을 상상해 볼 수도 있다.
I didn't mean anything else, but that's it
다른 뜻은 아니었는데 그게 다야
It's okay for you to tell him now
지금 그 사람에게 말해도 괜찮아요
If you want to trample even that point...
그 점까지 짓밟고 싶다면...
I will take this debt back today fiercely.
오늘은 이 빚을 맹렬히 갚아드리겠습니다.
please
제발
Those two gentlemen
그 두 분
It seems like there was a big fight over Eunjo.
은조 때문에 큰 싸움이 있었던 것 같다.
Who is that young man next to you?
옆에 있는 저 청년은 누구예요?
What a mystery
정말 미스터리네요
You are here
당신은 여기에 있습니다
Looking at his posture, he looks like he is the son of a wealthy family.
그의 자세를 보면 부유한 집안의 아들처럼 보인다.
Did Dr. Hong ever tell me who he was?
홍 박사님이 자신이 누구인지 나에게 말한 적이 있나요?
She never mentioned it
그녀는 그것에 대해 언급한 적이 없어요
When I saw her in the morning, her face was quite gloomy.
아침에 그녀를 봤을 때 그녀의 얼굴은 꽤 우울했습니다.
What about our senior official?
우리 고위 관계자는 어떻습니까?
He is absent from work today
그 사람 오늘 결근
Having said that
그렇게 말하면서
Have you heard anything about Ji Dong?
지동에 대해 들어본 적 있나요?
What happened to Ji Tong?
지통에게 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Could it be because of that rumor?
그 소문 때문이 아닐까?
Rumor?
소문?
End it quickly
빨리 끝내세요
Have you checked it out?
확인해 보셨나요?
This is Lord Du Chengzhi’s eldest son
이 사람은 Du Chengzhi 공의 장남입니다.
Items brought back from the Ming Dynasty to be transported to the palace
명나라에서 가져온 물건을 궁궐로 운반하다
Isn't this a seed?
이거 씨앗아닌가요?
where is this to be used
이건 어디에 쓰이나요
I've been feeling extremely sleepy and weak lately
요즘 너무 졸리고 허약한 느낌이 들어요
The weather is getting warmer, so you will be so sleepy, right?
날씨도 따뜻해져서 너무 졸리겠죠?
Right
오른쪽
Where did Lord Daoyue get that document?
도월경은 그 문서를 어디서 얻었습니까?
It is said that I picked it up by accident.
우연히 집어 들었다고 합니다.
Your Highness will not believe this statement, right?
전하께서는 이 말을 믿지 않으실 것입니다.
As long as my stepmother is alive
새엄마가 살아 있는 한
It seems like there are some fun old stories between the brothers.
형제들 사이에는 재미있는 옛날 이야기가 있는 것 같아요.
I'm sleepy
졸려요
All agree
모두 동의한다
Now that it's over, what else can there be to say in response?
이제 끝났으니 뭐라고 답할 수 있겠습니까?
No, it seems that I am overly worried.
아니, 지나치게 걱정하고 있는 것 같다.
The position of Da Sijian is still vacant.
Da Sijian의 자리는 아직 공석입니다.
Who should be put in this position...
누가 이 자리에 앉혀야 할지...
Hong Minzhi
홍민지
He is an old friend of yours, right?
그 사람은 당신의 오랜 친구죠?
Even now, I am still looking for Superintendent Hong Minzhi.
나는 지금도 홍민지 교육감을 찾고 있다.
It’s really hard to understand the Lord’s thoughts
주님의 생각을 이해하기란 정말 어렵습니다
He wants them all
그는 그들 모두를 원해요
The force of tyrants and the achievements of saintly kings
폭군의 힘과 성스러운 왕들의 업적
Don't miss anything
아무것도 놓치지 마세요
Superintendent Hong’s so-called blunt advice
홍 교육감의 이른바 무뚝뚝한 조언
They are all threatening my father.
그들은 모두 아버지를 위협하고 있습니다.
If the father cannot decide, then leave it to the child.
아버지가 결정할 수 없다면, 아이에게 맡기세요.
Didn’t Superintendent Hong stay ill for many years after he collapsed in the Gengwu year?
홍경감은 경오년에 쓰러진 뒤 여러 해 동안 병을 앓지 않았는가?
Didn't wake up until a year ago?
1년 전까지만 해도 깨어나지 않았나요?
Even if he died today and tomorrow, no one would be suspicious...
오늘 내일 죽어도 아무도 의심하지 않을텐데...
Be careful with your words
말을 조심하세요
He is my best friend in this life
그는 이생에서 나의 가장 친한 친구입니다
Please inform His Highness on my behalf
저를 대신하여 전하께 알려 주십시오.
I still don't have full freedom of movement
아직은 완전한 움직임의 자유를 누리지 못해요
Are you refusing?
거절하시나요?
If I sit back in the position of chief minister again,
내가 다시 총리 자리에 앉으면
Sooner or later my family will
조만간 우리 가족은
Will we encounter disaster like the Gengwu Year again?
경오년과 같은 재앙을 다시 맞이하게 될까요?
I can't let that child Eunjo
그 아이를 놔둘 수는 없어 은조
Bear that pain again
그 고통을 또 참아
Why are you so sure of the outcome?
왜 그렇게 결과를 확신하시나요?
Because I am a person who cannot bend down
나는 굽힐 수 없는 사람이니까
How about taking a teaching position in a college?
대학에서 교수직을 맡는 것은 어떻습니까?
I can write a recommendation letter for you
당신을 위해 추천서를 써드릴 수 있어요
That salary is enough to support the family.
그 급여는 가족을 부양하기에 충분합니다.
Always take care of you
항상 당신을 돌봐주세요
Pingyan thank you
핑옌 감사합니다
It's my turn to thank you
이제 내가 감사할 차례다
Save me from being the shameless person who takes the life of my best friend
내 가장 친한 친구의 생명을 앗아가는 뻔뻔한 사람이 되지 않도록 나를 구해주세요.
Should we ask them to retreat first?
먼저 물러나라고 해야 할까요?
I heard that the empress had an uneasy sleep at night
황후가 밤에 불안한 잠을 잤다는 소식을 들었습니다
My night sleep has long been dedicated to my only child
내 밤잠은 오랫동안 내 외동아들에게 바쳐졌어
On the other hand, the face of Zhongdian is not very good either.
반면에 중뎬의 얼굴도 별로 좋지 않다.
I am also because of my only husband...
나도 하나뿐인 남편 때문에..
Please forgive me for omitting the following
아래 내용을 생략한 점 양해 부탁드립니다
Fortunately, there is still a nave in this deserted palace.
다행히도 이 황량한 궁전에는 아직 신도석이 남아 있습니다.
Not long ago, the king entered Kangnyeong Palace
얼마 전 왕이 강녕궁에 들어왔습니다.
You should have heard about it
당신은 그것에 대해 들었어야 했어요
yes
응
What on earth was he thinking that he went to see the Lord alone?
그는 도대체 무슨 생각으로 혼자 주님을 만나러 갔을까요?
Although the inside story is unknown
내부 이야기는 알려지지 않았지만
But judging from the results, we are brothers who are of the same mind
하지만 결과로 볼 때 우리는 같은 마음을 가진 형제입니다.
Eliminate corrupt officials
부패한 공직자를 제거하라
Just treat it as such
그냥 그렇게 처리하세요
The Lord’s temptation must have a reason
주님의 유혹에는 이유가 있어야 합니다
Have you forgotten what happened in the Gengwu Year?
Gengwu Year에 무슨 일이 있었는지 잊으셨습니까?
Then wait for the tragedy...
그렇다면 비극을 기다려라...
How could it be forgotten so easily
어떻게 그렇게 쉽게 잊혀질 수 있나요?
I said unnecessary things
쓸데없는 말을 했네요
Let's not talk about politics here.
여기서는 정치 얘기를 하지 맙시다.
Right
오른쪽
I'm also inquiring about Maharaja's marriage.
마하라자의 결혼에 대해서도 문의드립니다.
Really?
정말?
Concubine
첩
Is the Maharaja inside?
마하라자가 안에 있나요?
I must finalize the marriage today...
오늘 결혼을 마무리해야 하는데...
Why is the imperial doctor also there...
황실 의사도 왜 거기에...
Is Yue'er sick?
Yue'er 아픈가요?
No other symptoms
다른 증상 없음
Just these few days...
바로 요 며칠...
Feeling extremely restless
매우 불안한 느낌
It’s really…
정말…
Why is this music so sad?
이 음악은 왜 이렇게 슬픈 걸까요?
Didn’t I tell you to boost your spirits?
내가 기운을 북돋아 주라고 말하지 않았나요?
My stomach hurts
배가 아프다
Don't you think it's funny?
재미없다고 생각하지 않나요?
Why is it funny
왜 웃기지?
Because I'm laughing
웃고 있으니까
I already said I want to laugh, can't you agree with me?
이미 웃고 싶다고 했는데, 동의할 수 없나요?
How about grabbing it?
잡아보는 건 어떨까요?
Spot the mole first, then take revenge
먼저 두더지를 찾아낸 다음 복수하세요
what do you think
어떻게 생각하세요?
Sir
선생님
I am the king of this country
나는 이 나라의 왕이다
If you want to grab it, are you afraid that you won't be able to grab it?
잡고 싶어도 잡지 못할까 봐 두려우신가요?
I'll show you
내가 보여줄게
What is omnipresent power?
편재하는 힘이란 무엇입니까?
She was completely unmoved
그녀는 전혀 움직이지 않았습니다
The wealth and power I have
내가 가진 부와 권력
status, bearing, appearance
상태, 베어링, 외관
Most people are tempted by just one of these items
대부분의 사람들은 다음 항목 중 하나만으로 유혹을 받습니다.
She just won't be tempted by anything.
그녀는 아무것도 유혹하지 않을 것입니다.
This is from the Royal Medical Clinic
이건 왕립의료원에서 온 거야
A document recording the illness of your Majesty
폐하의 병을 기록한 문서
The Empress ordered that the disease be spread to medical clinics across the country
황후는 이 병이 전국의 의료기관으로 퍼지도록 명령했다.
Gathering everyone’s wisdom to find out the name of the disease
모두의 지혜를 모아 질병의 이름을 알아내다
Fire sickness?
화재병?
Could it be madness?
광기일까요?
do you have any ideas
당신은 어떤 아이디어가 있나요
Are you asking me?
나한테 묻는 거야?
Now we need everyone to come up with ideas
이제 모두가 아이디어를 내야 합니다.
Even just one person’s idea is important
한 사람의 아이디어라도 중요하다
Don't worry too much. Let's listen.
너무 걱정하지 마세요. 들어 보자.
Happy, Angry, Worry, Thought, Sadness, Fear, Surprise
행복, 화, 걱정, 생각, 슬픔, 두려움, 놀라움
From the point of view of disorder of the seven emotions
칠정의 혼란이라는 관점에서
I'd venture to guess that I might be suffering from depression.
우울증을 겪고 있는 게 아닐까 추측해봅니다.
Don’t you think that Maharaja’s symptoms are very similar to lovelorn?
마하라자의 증상이 사랑에 빠진 것과 매우 비슷하다고 생각하지 않나요?
Lovelorn?
사랑에 빠진?
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
From today on we won't meet again
오늘부터 우리는 다시는 만나지 않을 거예요
That's what I meant
그게 내 뜻이야
Lovelorn…
사랑에 빠진…
Is it such a painful thing?
그게 그렇게 괴로운 일인가요?
what did you say
뭐라고 했어?
nothing
아무것도
How can anyone dare to get rid of the Maharaja?
누가 감히 마하라자를 제거할 수 있겠습니까?
On the contrary, I think it was a wise move for the medical woman to reject you.
오히려 의료인이 당신을 거부한 것이 현명한 행동이었다고 생각합니다.
Meet and separate rashly
성급하게 만나고 헤어지고
Wouldn't it be of no use to her?
그 사람한테는 아무 소용이 없겠죠?
Who said I was rash?
내가 성급하다고 누가 말했나요?
Are you planning to take her as your concubine?
그녀를 첩으로 삼을 계획이신가요?
Not married yet
아직 결혼하지 않았습니다
If the concubine knew about it
첩이 이 사실을 알았다면
There will definitely be a fuss afterwards
나중에 난리날 것이 분명하다
You made your wishful thinking too early
너무 일찍 희망을 품었구나
Not to mention it was a trick, it didn't even start.
그것은 속임수였다는 것은 말할 것도 없고, 심지어 시작도 되지 않았습니다.
That's right
그렇죠
Since it hasn't started yet
아직 시작하지 않았기 때문에
Of course there is nothing to forget
물론 잊어버릴 일은 없지
Yes
예
Her face is still imprinted in my mind
아직도 그 사람 얼굴이 머릿속에 각인되어 있어서
Your expression is getting more and more interesting the more I look at it
네 표정은 볼수록 재밌어
To put it bluntly, I really don’t like that medical woman.
솔직하게 말하면 나는 그 의사 여자를 별로 좋아하지 않는다.
They already have fiancés
그 사람들은 이미 약혼자가 있어
Why did I do that to you that night?
그날 밤 내가 왜 너한테 그랬어?
Here we go again, I really can’t stand it
또 가네, 정말 못 참겠어
what's going on
무슨 일이야?
Destroyed?
파괴되었나요?
Are you praying for their relationship to break up now?
당신은 지금 그들의 관계가 무너지기를 기도하고 있습니까?
Lord Superintendent
주 교육감
Are you ready to leave the palace?
궁전을 떠날 준비가 되셨나요?
Do you want to walk back together?
같이 다시 걸어갈래?
are you waiting for me
나를 기다리고 있나요?
can't i do this
나 이거 할 수 없어?
Of course that's good
물론 그거 좋지
what are you thinking
무슨 생각을 하고 있어?
This scene feels strange to me
이 장면이 이상하게 느껴지네요
Until a year ago you were still bedridden
1년 전까지만 해도 당신은 여전히 침대에 누워 있었습니다.
I never thought I'd be able to walk with you like this
이렇게 너와 함께 걸을 수 있을 거라고는 생각도 못 했어
Pingyan recommended a position to me
Pingyan이 나에게 포지션을 추천했습니다.
He said there is an academy in Nanyuan that needs teachers
난위안에 교사가 필요한 학원이 있다고 하더군요
I agreed
나는 동의했다
Do you actually have to go that far away?
실제로 그렇게 멀리 가야 합니까?
With your current physical condition, it should be difficult for you to bear the burden.
현재의 몸 상태로는 부담을 감당하기 어려울 것입니다.
Not too forced
너무 강요하지 않음
Instead of wasting time here
여기서 시간을 낭비하는 것보다
Maybe it wouldn't be so hard to teach there.
어쩌면 그곳에서 가르치는 것이 그리 어렵지 않을 수도 있습니다.
When do you plan to leave?
언제 떠날 계획인가요?
I'm leaving in a few days
나 며칠 뒤에 떠날 거야
Should arrive on the day classes start
수업 시작하는 날 도착해야 함
So will you set off before the wedding?
그럼 결혼식 전에 출발할 건가요?
Yeah, what a pity
응, 안됐구나
It turns out that the adults made this trip because they couldn’t let go.
알고 보니 어른들은 놓지 못해서 이 여행을 하게 된 것입니다.
Leaving before the wedding might be a good thing
결혼식 전에 떠나는 게 좋을지도 몰라
How I want to see your rouged face
너의 붉은 얼굴이 얼마나 보고 싶은지
I will cheer up
응원하겠습니다
Have a good wedding
결혼식 잘 보내세요
Then let me help you prepare the medicinal materials you need to take on the way.
그럼 가는 길에 가져가야 할 약재 준비를 제가 도와드리겠습니다.
You don't have to worry
걱정하지 않아도 돼요
If you want to find good medicinal materials
좋은 약재를 찾고 싶다면
You have to start looking for it now
지금부터 찾기 시작해야 해요
Even as a wicked woman
사악한 소녀라도
Maybe I’d also imagine being remembered like this.
어쩌면 나 또한 이렇게 기억되는 것을 상상해 볼 수도 있다.
Are you planning how to break off the engagement again?
약혼을 다시 끊는 방법을 계획하고 있습니까?
Don't use admiration as a pretext
감탄을 구실로 삼지 말라
What's the real reason you want to ruin your marriage?
결혼 생활을 망치고 싶은 진짜 이유는 무엇입니까?
where are you going
어디로 가시나요?
to ruin this marriage.
이 결혼을 망치려고.
The king actually had a relationship with a medical woman
왕은 실제로 의사와 관계를 맺었습니다
Other than that, there is nothing unusual
그 외에는 특이한 점은 없습니다
However, the young master met the Maharaja at the Huimin Office before going back.
그러나 젊은 스승은 돌아가기 전 희민사에서 마하라자를 만났다.
Now I can finally see my father.
이제 드디어 아버지를 볼 수 있게 되었습니다.
I've been here several times but all failed, and I feel deeply disappointed.
나는 여기에 여러 번 왔지만 모두 실패했고 깊은 실망감을 느꼈습니다.
Who did you just go see?
방금 누구 보러 갔어요?
What's going on with this concern-filled question?
걱정 가득한 이 질문에 무슨 일이 벌어지고 있는 걸까요?
I don't seem to deserve this kind of treatment
난 이런 대우를 받을 자격이 없는 것 같아
Yes
예
Your only advantage is that you know how many layers you have
유일한 장점은 얼마나 많은 레이어가 있는지 알 수 있다는 것입니다.
Dad
아빠
I overheard your conversation with your mother
나는 당신이 어머니와 나누는 대화를 우연히 들었습니다.
Am I not my mother’s biological flesh and blood?
나는 어머니의 생물학적 살과 피가 아닌가?
Is he the son of a prostitute from a humble background?
그는 비천한 집안 출신의 창녀의 아들인가?
so stupid
너무 멍청해
If you pretend not to hear
못 들은 척 하면
At least I can deceive myself
적어도 나는 나 자신을 속일 수 있다
Then why do you want me to grow up as your eldest son?
그럼 왜 내가 당신의 큰 아들로 자라길 바라나요?
Is it because dad only has one son, his elder brother?
아빠에게는 아들 하나, 즉 형밖에 없기 때문일까요?
you don't need to be disappointed
실망할 필요는 없어
To seal the mouth of your prostitute mother
네 창녀 어미의 입을 봉하게 하려 함이라
I paid a lot of price
나는 많은 대가를 지불했다
So you are not worthless
그러니 당신은 쓸모없는 사람이 아닙니다.
The livestock sold cost a lot of money.
팔린 가축에는 많은 비용이 들었습니다.
Are you taking credit from me?
당신은 나에게서 공을 빼앗고 있습니까?
I have already helped you get the number one scholar that your government is so eager for.
나는 이미 귀하의 정부가 그토록 열망하는 최고의 학자를 얻는 데 도움을 주었습니다.
In the future, I will also get you the official position you want.
앞으로는 당신이 원하는 공식적인 자리도 내어줄게요.
Now it's my turn to take some credit
이제 내가 신용을 얻을 차례야
Please cancel your marriage to the Zhongdian family
중뎬 가문과의 결혼을 취소해주세요
I don't want to be a stud who just sows seeds
난 씨앗만 뿌리는 종은 되고 싶지 않아
It's a pity that your usefulness only ends here
당신의 쓸모가 여기서 끝나다니 안타깝네요
I don't want to imitate someone
누군가를 흉내내고 싶지 않아요
Let any defective products come out
불량품이 나오도록 해주세요
So you just want to ruin my good deeds?
그럼 당신은 단지 내 선행을 망치고 싶은 겁니까?
See you are so angry
봐, 너 너무 화났어
It seems that I should have succeeded
성공했어야 했을 것 같은데
are you injured
당신은 부상을 입었습니까?
This guy...
이 사람...
What happened to him
그에게 무슨 일이 일어났는가
Have you mentioned the secret record to Zai Yi?
자이에게 비밀 기록을 언급했나요?
No
아니요
Didn’t you say it’s not yet time?
아직은 때가 아니라고 하지 않았나요?
This is the medicine we adults need to take
우리 어른들이 꼭 먹어야 할 약이에요
Please take more trouble
더 고민해주세요
No problem
문제없어
Come
오세요
she is smiling again
그녀는 또 웃고 있어
What's so funny
뭐가 그렇게 웃긴데?
Uncle, please give me a pound of Huang Qi.
삼촌, 황기(Huang Qi) 한 파운드 주세요.
what are you doing
뭐하는거야?
Didn’t I say I would ask you to repay me twice as much?
내가 두 배로 갚아달라고 하지 않았나요?
Let me go, I tell you to let me go
놔줘 놔달라고 해
Are you like this because of what happened last time?
저번 일 때문에 이러시는 건가요?
I think you are an eyesore
내 생각엔 당신이 눈에 거슬리는 사람인 것 같아요
What happened to me
나에게 무슨 일이 일어났는가
A mere evil girl dares to act like a younger sister
단순한 악녀가 감히 여동생 행세를 하고 있다
What else does Shen Qing sacrifice for his blind father?
Shen Qing은 눈먼 아버지를 위해 또 무엇을 희생합니까?
He even dreamed of being happy until old age
그는 노년까지 행복을 꿈꿨다
All this is an eyesore to me
이 모든 것이 나에게는 눈에 거슬리는 일이다
It's better to live a miserable life
차라리 비참한 삶을 사는 것이 낫다
Don't just smile when nothing happens
아무 일 없을 때 그냥 웃지 마세요
Even if it’s crying, getting angry, or being resentful, that’s fine
울어도, 화를 내어도, 원망스러워도 괜찮아
Because in real life
왜냐면 실생활에서는
There is no emperor who will come forward to rescue Shen Qing
Shen Qing을 구출하러 나올 황제는 없습니다.
So what is your conclusion?
그래서 당신의 결론은 무엇입니까?
Do you want me to break off the engagement again?
내가 다시 약혼을 파기하길 원하시나요?
This marriage…
이번 결혼은…
No
아니요
It should be a transaction
거래가 되어야지
This deal…
이번 거래는…
as you said
당신이 말했듯이
She's just a naughty girl like me
그 사람도 나처럼 장난꾸러기일 뿐이야
Just a struggle to survive
그저 살아남기 위한 몸부림
So I can't give up easily
그래서 쉽게 포기할 수가 없어요
thank you for your charity
당신의 자선 활동에 감사드립니다
Why are you so careless?
왜 그렇게 부주의합니까?
What's going on? What's your expression?
무슨 일이야? 당신의 표정은 어떻습니까?
I asked you what happened
무슨 일이냐고 물었더니
Is something wrong?
뭔가 문제가 있나요?
Of course I would be frightened if you appeared out of nowhere.
물론 갑자기 나타나면 겁이 나겠지만요.
Why are you here...
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
Are you here to find me?
나를 찾으러 오셨나요?
Don't be sentimental
감정적으로 굴지 마세요
I originally wanted to answer you like this
원래는 이렇게 대답하고 싶었는데
But you were right
하지만 당신 말이 옳았어요
I went to the Huimin Office
희민 사무실에 갔어요
I heard you were looking for a medicine dealer
네가 약상을 찾고 있다고 들었어
So I chased after him relentlessly.
그래서 나는 그를 끈질기게 쫓아다녔다.
why are you looking for me
왜 나를 찾고 있나요?
when are you going to get married
언제 결혼할 거예요?
Next year? Or the year after tomorrow?
내년? 아니면 내일 모레?
It's no good if we keep bumping into each other
계속 부딪히면 안 돼
It's better not to give him hope
그에게 희망을 주지 않는 것이 낫다
Ten days later
열흘 후
Ten days…
열흘…
I'm afraid we don't have time to flirt or laugh.
우리에겐 장난을 치거나 웃을 시간이 없을 것 같아요.
Enjoy the atmosphere and get to know each other better
분위기를 즐기고 서로를 더 잘 알아가세요
what
뭐
what do you like
당신은 무엇을 좋아하나요?
Food, scenery, jewelry, paintings, or musical preferences?
음식, 풍경, 보석, 그림, 음악적 취향?
No. Where is a better place to start?
아니요. 어디서부터 시작하는 것이 더 좋을까요?
That... where is the nearest cloth shop?
그... 가장 가까운 옷가게는 어디에 있나요?
We need to go there first
우리 먼저 거기로 가야 해
Wait, wait a moment
잠깐, 잠깐만요
Are you kidding me now?
지금 장난하는 거야?
If I just wanted to make a joke
그냥 농담하고 싶었다면
Will I cling to you like this without respecting myself?
나 자신을 존중하지 않고 이렇게 당신에게 매달릴 것인가?
Am I the only one who thinks this is sudden?
갑작스럽다고 생각하는 건 저뿐인가요?
Me too
나도
This kind of behavior is no different from that of a lunatic.
이런 행동은 미치광이의 행동과 다르지 않습니다.
It turns out that on the day we first met
알고보니 우리 처음 만난 날
I didn't make a mistake
나는 실수하지 않았다
Just think of the fool part as prescient.
바보 부분을 예지력이 있다고 생각하십시오.
Have you forgotten?
잊으셨나요?
What about me?
나는 어떻습니까?
My fiancé is the only one in my heart
내 약혼자는 내 마음속에 있는 유일한 사람이에요
That guy treats you...
그 사람이 당신을 대하는군요...
Why are so many people in the world attracted to these women?
왜 세계의 많은 사람들이 이 여성들에게 매력을 느끼는 걸까요?
So disgusting
너무 역겨워
Very annoying
매우 짜증나
Are you sure it's the same person as the one from a few days ago?
며칠 전의 사람과 같은 사람이 맞나요?
Or are you just so unreasonable?
아니면 너무 불합리한가요?
If I am really being unreasonable
내가 정말 무리한 짓을 하고 있다면
You can't do anything to me at all
넌 나한테 아무것도 할 수 없어
The reason why I didn’t ask about your fiancé’s family background
약혼자 집안 배경을 묻지 않은 이유
It's because I want to use all the coercive means I can use
내가 할 수 있는 모든 강압적인 수단을 다 쓰고 싶기 때문이다.
Saved until the last moment
마지막 순간까지 저장됨
I don't want to become a mean person
못된 사람이 되고 싶지 않아
I hope you can endure it as much as possible
최대한 버텨주셨으면 좋겠습니다
I'm trying to make you change your mind.
나는 당신의 마음을 바꾸도록 노력하고 있습니다.
I really can't understand
정말 이해할 수가 없어요
How many times have you met me?
당신은 나를 몇 번이나 만났나요?
How many times do we need to see each other again?
우리는 몇 번이나 다시 만나야 할까요?
If I want you to understand why I do this
내가 왜 이런 짓을 하는지 이해해주길 바란다면
No…
아니…
I won't bother to understand
이해하려고 애쓰지 않을게
I'm leaving first
나 먼저 갈게
Be careful on your way
가는 길 조심하세요
You'd better be honest
솔직하게 말하는 게 좋을 거야
Are you trying to run away from me now?
지금 나한테서 도망치려는 거야?
because you are scared
왜냐하면 당신은 무서워서
Afraid?
두렵나요?
What does this mean?
이것은 무엇을 의미합니까?
You know it well yourself
당신 스스로도 잘 알고 있죠
I reiterate
나는 반복한다
Me to my fiancé…
나는 약혼자에게…
You must not be in love, right?
사랑에 빠지면 안 되겠죠?
If that's the case
그렇다면
Then how come you did that night...
그럼 그날 밤엔 어떻게 됐나요...
I originally planned to go along with your improvised lie.
원래는 네 즉석 거짓말에 동조할 생각이었어.
When you draw the line and push me away
선을 긋고 나를 밀어낼 때
I also thought about simply pretending not to know and turning around.
나도 그냥 모른 척하고 돌아서볼까 하는 생각도 들었다.
But I don't want to do that
하지만 난 그러고 싶지 않아
So…
그래서…
Good
좋음
I'll tell you the truth
나는 당신에게 진실을 말할 것입니다
That's right, that night
그렇죠, 그날 밤
I decided that night that I was going to have a
나는 그날 밤에 한잔 하기로 결정했다.
People like me in North Korea
나 같은 사람들이 북한에 있어요.
Most people choose marriage
대부분의 사람들은 결혼을 선택한다.
for me
나를 위해
wealth, success, fame
부, 성공, 명성
My family and even myself
우리 가족은 물론 나 자신까지도
Among the many things that people value
사람들이 중요하게 여기는 많은 것 중에
What I thought was the least relevant to me
나에게 가장 관련성이 없다고 생각한 것
It's love
사랑이야
But the night I made up my mind to get married
하지만 내가 결혼하기로 결심한 날 밤
This is the first time I asked myself
나 자신에게 물어본 건 이번이 처음이다
If I…
만약 내가…
What should I do if I miss something important?
중요한 것을 놓치면 어떻게 해야 합니까?
This question makes me very uneasy
이 질문은 나를 매우 불안하게 만든다
It seems that I have also made myself very unlucky.
나 역시도 매우 불행한 일을 겪은 것 같다.
That's when I saw you
그때 내가 너를 봤어
I saw a man who had been waiting for me for more than two hours
두 시간 넘게 나를 기다리고 있는 남자를 봤다
Suddenly I felt like I had become the protagonist in a folk legend
문득 전설 속 주인공이 된 기분이 들었어요
That's it
그게 다야
escape reality
현실에서 벗어나다
Run to you
너에게 달려가
Blinded by self-pity
자기연민에 눈이 멀어
casually to a strange man
우연히 낯선 남자에게
pour out one's misfortune
불행을 쏟아내다
But I don't want to be stuck with that story now
하지만 지금은 그 이야기에 얽매이고 싶지 않아요
lie
거짓말
Please stop following me
팔로우를 중단해주세요
I'm the one who got dumped
버림받은 건 나야
Why are you angry instead?
오히려 왜 화를 내나요?
I just need one sentence
한 문장만 있으면 돼
I just need your permission
당신의 허락이 필요해요
Why is he so serious?
왜 그렇게 진지해?
I'm different from my dad
나는 아빠와 달라요
if it were me
나라면
As early as the day when the disaster occurred in the Gengwu year
이르면 경무년(景君年)에 재난이 발생한 날
I'll kill all the rats in your house.
너희 집에 있는 쥐들을 다 죽여버리겠다.
Although I don't want to hurt him
그 사람에게 상처를 주고 싶지는 않지만
But I have to be cruel
하지만 잔인하게 굴어야 해
I have already answered you
나는 이미 당신에게 대답했습니다.
Because of my low status
내 지위가 낮기 때문에
So even rejection is insignificant?
그러면 거절도 별 의미가 없나요?
That's not what I meant
내 말은 그런 뜻이 아니었어
Did you misinterpret it or did it on purpose?
잘못 해석한 걸까요, 아니면 일부러 그런 걸까요?
What about me?
나는 어떻습니까?
Not the kind of person who can freely say whatever he thinks
자기 생각을 자유롭게 말할 수 있는 그런 사람이 아니다.
Unilateral display of any emotional identity
감정적 정체성을 일방적으로 표시
I must endure, hold on, hide
견뎌야 해, 버텨야 해, 숨겨야 해
Nothing can be shown
아무것도 표시할 수 없습니다.
Therefore
그러므로
I won't be swayed by a moment of childishness
한 순간의 유치함에도 흔들리지 않아
This…
이…
it's me
나야
the gap between you
너 사이의 간격
Childish?
유치하다?
That's right
그렇죠
Just like you said, I don't need to look at people's faces
네 말대로 난 사람 얼굴 볼 필요 없어
Growing up in an environment without any scruples
아무런 양심의 가책도 없는 환경에서 자라
I admit what I said casually
내가 무심코 한 말은 인정한다
It’s because you didn’t consider the other party’s confession
상대방의 고백을 고려하지 않았기 때문이다
It is also a kind of love that is not respectful enough.
그것은 또한 충분히 존중받지 못하는 일종의 사랑이기도 합니다.
I'm not curious at all about the gap you mentioned.
말씀하신 격차는 전혀 궁금하지 않습니다.
Because I don't need to understand
이해할 필요는 없으니까
I don’t want to pretend to understand just now
지금은 이해하는 척 하기 싫어
But
하지만
Even with this status
이 상태에서도
Before appearing in front of the woman you like
좋아하는 여자 앞에 나타나기 전에
I will also practice it dozens or hundreds of times in my mind
저도 마음속으로 수십번 수백번 연습해보겠습니다
My steps are always heavy and hesitant
내 발걸음은 늘 무겁고 머뭇거려
Usually this kind of thing
보통 이런 일이
everyone calls it courage
다들 그걸 용기라 부르지
But you are so heartless
그런데 당신은 너무 무정해요
(You're my everything to me)
(당신은 나에게 전부입니다)
I'm leaving
나는 떠난다
(The one that attracted me)
(나를 매료시킨 사람)
(named your dazzling sunshine to me)
(나에게 당신의 눈부신 햇살이라 이름을 지어주었어요)
(The moment I see you again)
(다시 만나는 순간)
(My heart is calling you)
(내 마음이 널 부르고 있어)
(We Again Again)
(우리 또 다시)
(You're my everything to me)
(당신은 나에게 전부입니다)
(The one that attracted me)
(나를 매료시킨 사람)
(named your dazzling sunshine to me)
(나에게 당신의 눈부신 햇살이라 이름을 지어주었어요)
(You're my everything to me)
(당신은 나에게 전부입니다)
(The moment I see you again)
(다시 만나는 순간)
(Being with you like a dream again)
(다시 꿈처럼 너와 함께 있는 것)
Mother
어머니
I'm so hungry
너무 배가 고파요
You stay
당신은 머물러
I'm going to get snacks
나는 간식을 사러 갈거야
Smelly girl, leave this house quickly.
냄새나는 소녀야, 빨리 이 집에서 나가라.
Do that to me...
나한테 그런 짓을 해줘...
Are you saying that our Eunjo is going to marry your grandfather?
우리 은조가 할아버지랑 결혼한다는 말씀이신가요?
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
what memory is this
이게 무슨 기억이야?
The guy who sold his evil daughter to make ends meet
돈벌이를 위해 못된 딸을 팔아먹은 남자
The wine went smoothly.
와인은 순조롭게 진행되었습니다.
Damn...
젠장...
Mother
어머니
When is Eunjo's marriage scheduled?
은조 결혼 예정일은 언제인가요?
There are only ten days left now
이제 열흘밖에 남지 않았네요
When did father say he was going there?
아버지는 언제 거기로 간다고 하셨나요?
five days later
5일 후
Damn it, don't care
젠장, 상관하지 마
No matter what she wants
그녀가 원하는 것이 무엇이든
None of my business
내 상관은 없어
none of my business
내 알바는 아니야
I heard you were looking for me
당신이 나를 찾고 있다고 들었어요
The marriage to the Middle Temple family will not be withdrawn.
중성전 가문과의 혼인은 철회되지 않습니다.
Husband and wife should be of one mind
남편과 아내가 한마음이 되어야 합니다
I should also let my wife know that I exist
아내에게도 내가 존재한다는 사실을 알려야 한다
If she knew I was a beast
내가 짐승인 걸 그녀가 알았더라면
That lady from a highly respected scholar-bureaucrat's family
매우 존경받는 학자 관료 집안의 그 여인
How many tears will you shed?
얼마나 많은 눈물을 흘릴 것인가?
That despicable evil girl is willing to do it for her father
그 비열하고 사악한 소녀는 아버지를 위해 기꺼이 그것을 할 것입니다
Became the old man's concubine
노인의 첩이 되다
Why are you mentioning that girl's name now?
왜 지금 그 여자 이름을 거론하는 겁니까?
You should follow that boy Eunjo's example
그 소년 은조의 예를 따라야 해
You want me to shut up and be sold
넌 내가 닥치고 팔려가길 원해
Just like that girl?
그 여자랑 똑같아?
You thought that as long as it was as you said
당신이 말한 대로라면 넌 그렇게 생각했을 거야
Refuse to be a sowing stallion
씨를 뿌리는 종마가 되기를 거부하라
Can you keep your self-esteem?
자존감을 지킬 수 있나요?
Enzu, that kid knows it very well
엔즈, 그 아이는 그걸 아주 잘 알아
Lowly people don't deserve that kind of thing in the first place
낮은 사람들은 애초에 그런 일을 받을 자격이 없습니다
You cannot ask the daughter of the Middle Temple family
미들 템플 가문의 딸에게 물어볼 수는 없습니다
No
아니요
You can't identify yourself to anyone
누구에게도 자신의 신원을 밝힐 수 없습니다.
I give you name, wealth and fame
이름과 부와 명성을 네게 주노라
None of you...
너희 중 누구도...
Can't give up
포기할 수 없어
That's the real you
그게 진짜 너야
Be careful on the road
길에서 조심하세요
I heard that the environment there is good and the scenery is beautiful
그곳은 환경도 좋고 풍경도 아름답다고 들었어요
enjoy it
즐겨라
But that…
하지만 그건…
At least watch Eun Jo's marriage before leaving.
적어도 떠나기 전에 은조의 결혼을 지켜보세요.
now
지금
You are the head of this family
당신은 이 가족의 가장입니다
Take good care of them for me
나를 위해 그것들을 잘 돌봐주세요
Why do you put the responsibility on me?
왜 나에게 책임을 맡기는 걸까요?
You guy, now you also...
너도 이제 너도...
Really
정말로
Hello
안녕하세요
Don't you have anything to say?
할 말 없나요?
It's up to you to decide your fate.
당신의 운명을 결정하는 것은 당신에게 달려 있습니다.
Abominable
혐오스러운
That guy looked like this even on the day I left.
그 사람은 내가 떠나던 날에도 이런 모습이었어.
I'm so sorry
정말 미안해요
No
아니요
Medicinal materials prepared for you
당신을 위해 준비한 약재
Please ask the wine lady at the inn to cook it for you and drink it.
여관의 와인 아줌마에게 요리해서 마셔달라고 부탁하세요.
I'm sorry for leaving you alone to prepare for the wedding.
결혼식 준비하느라 혼자 남겨두어서 미안해요.
No need to worry
걱정할 필요 없어
As long as you arrive safely
무사히 도착하는 한
I heard you've been looking for me
당신이 나를 찾고 있다고 들었어요
Has everyone else quit?
다른 사람들은 다 그만뒀나요?
Can't give you much time
시간을 많이 줄 수는 없어요
Does the Lord also know?
주님도 아시나요?
The incense you brought into your bedroom
침실에 가져온 향
What is its origin
그 유래는 무엇인가
Keep smelling that fragrance
그 향기를 계속 맡아보세요
will cause confusion
혼란을 야기할 것이다
Loss of ability to discern things
사물을 분별하는 능력의 상실
In the end, it will become an empty shell that is no different from the corpse.
결국 그것은 시체와 다를 바 없는 빈 껍질이 될 것이다.
Be your guy's leader
당신의 남자의 리더가 되세요
Lord thought it was a painkiller
주님은 그것이 진통제라고 생각하셨습니다.
Let me know if you have symptoms of poisoning
중독 증상이 있으면 알려주세요.
All agree
모두 동의한다
Is this North Korea what you got?
이것이 북한이 당신이 가지고 있는 것입니까?
you guy
너네
Aren't you afraid of divine punishment?
신의 형벌이 두렵지 않습니까?
You said he has been doing this for several days
며칠째 이런 짓을 하고 있다고 하더군요
Are you all just focusing on fishing?
다들 낚시에만 집중하고 계시나요?
Has your Majesty ever dreamed of becoming a fisherman?
폐하께서 어부가 되는 꿈을 꾸셨던 적이 있습니까?
If you can’t catch a woman, then catch something else.
여자를 잡을 수 없다면 다른 걸 잡으세요.
This should be the mentality
이런 마인드가 있어야지
To gossip behind the person's back is to stir up trouble.
그 사람의 뒤에서 험담을 하는 것은 문제를 일으키는 것입니다.
If you want to say something, I will not be able to see or hear you.
당신이 무슨 말을 하고 싶어도 나는 당신을 볼 수도, 들을 수도 없습니다.
Don't make me upset
나를 화나게 하지 마세요
If you want to stir up trouble, you should also show some sincerity.
문제를 일으키고 싶다면 성실함도 보여야합니다.
This is pretense of gossiping.
이것은 험담을 하는 척하는 것입니다.
How long do you plan to do this?
언제까지 이 일을 할 계획인가요?
I need to know the answer to this
이것에 대한 답을 알아야 해요
Tell me when you know it too
너도 알면 말해줘
Really
정말로
Your Majesty
폐하
Actually, I came to you to report something.
사실은 신고할 게 있어서 왔습니다.
Rumors about a lucky boy are spreading in the market
시장에는 운 좋은 소년에 관한 소문이 퍼지고 있다.
What rumors
무슨 소문이 있니?
I heard about the person who stole the secret record of the great minister's remonstrance on corruption.
대장관의 비리 탄핵 비밀기록을 훔친 사람에 대한 이야기를 들었습니다.
It's Ji Tong
지통이에요
That's not a rumor, it's a fact
그거 루머가 아니라 사실이에요
That's right
그렇죠
I'm also confused
나도 많이 혼란스러워
Didn't you say that only the three of us know?
우리 셋만 안다고 하지 않았나요?
There is indeed someone who knows
진짜 아는 사람이 있구나
Who?
누구?
Ji Tong
지통
Didn't he ever ask for help hiding it?
그는 그것을 숨기는 데 도움을 요청한 적이 없나요?
What is the origin of the things you stole?
당신이 훔친 물건의 출처는 무엇입니까?
Maybe it's because the incident became too big
어쩌면 사건이 너무 커져서 그런가봐
This also gave him the desire to strive for fame and credit.
이것은 또한 그에게 명성과 신용을 위해 노력하려는 열망을 갖게 했습니다.
Or rather
아니면 오히려
He was taking advantage of the Maharaja from the beginning
그는 처음부터 마하라자를 이용하고 있었습니다.
We need to investigate in a different direction
다른 방향으로 조사해야 합니다
Change direction?
방향을 바꾸시겠습니까?
Track down the secret records
비밀 기록을 추적하세요
I understand
나는 이해한다
When looking for the owner of the secret record, you will naturally find Ji Tong
비밀기록의 주인을 찾으면 자연스럽게 지통을 발견하게 된다
Since it records the fact that Da Si Jian was involved in corruption,
Da Si Jian이 부패에 연루된 사실을 기록하고 있기 때문에
person who writes secret records
비밀기록을 쓰는 사람
It's very possible that they are people who want to seize Da Si Jian's weakness.
Da Si Jian의 약점을 잡으려는 사람들일 가능성이 높습니다.
You go see Da Sijian and find out what he says.
Da Sijian을 만나서 그가 말하는 것을 알아보세요.
He is too hostile to me, so he will definitely not speak.
그는 나에게 너무 적대적이어서 절대로 말을 하지 않을 것이다.
Today's treatment has ended
오늘 진료가 끝났습니다
Come again next time
다음에 또 오세요
They are the children of Guangtong Bridge
그들은 광통대교의 아이들이다
Come here
여기로 오세요
Isn’t it your wedding tomorrow?
내일 결혼식 아니지?
Go and have some rest, and take a shift with someone else.
가서 좀 쉬고, 다른 사람과 교대 근무를 하세요.
Why are you like this lately?
요즘 왜 이러세요?
I'll sort out the rest. You can go back.
나머지는 제가 정리하겠습니다. 돌아갈 수 있습니다.
When did you have dinner?
언제 저녁을 먹었나요?
If you were born as a rice insect
벼곤충으로 태어났다면
I'm afraid the whole year will be a drought.
올해 내내 가뭄이 들까 두렵습니다.
There is nothing to give now
이제 줄 게 아무것도 없어
Is this also possible?
이것도 가능합니까?
Is it for me?
나를 위한 것인가?
This gift is too good, right?
이 선물 너무 좋지 않나요?
So beautiful
너무 아름다워
Use this to support
이것을 사용하여 지원하십시오.
This little monk is quite smart.
이 작은 스님은 꽤 똑똑해요.
This is enough to re-pave the floor of the Buddhist hall.
이것은 불당 바닥을 다시 포장하기에 충분합니다.
What about me?
나는 어떻습니까?
This is the bracelet that authenticates me as a big benefactor.
이것은 나를 큰 은인으로 인증하는 팔찌이다.
Your one tael of silver is not worthy of it
너희 은 한 톨도 아깝지 아니하도다
The kids these days don’t even reply.
요즘 애들은 대답도 안해요.
He is practicing silently
그는 조용히 연습하고 있다
It happened to rain
비가 왔다
Your Majesty
폐하
You'll catch a cold like this
이러다 감기 걸리겠다
It seems like the rain won't stop tomorrow, right?
내일은 비가 그치지 않을 것 같죠?
It seems
것 같다
But…
하지만…
what are you looking at
무엇을 보고 있나요?
muddy water
진흙탕
It rained even on the wedding day
결혼식날에도 비가 내렸어요
Even the weather is gloomy and gloomy
날씨도 우울하고 우울해
The rain stopped in the early morning
비는 이른 아침에 그쳤어요
Do you think it will rain again?
또 비가 올 것 같아?
Abominable
혐오스러운
What's wrong? What happened?
무슨 일이야? 무슨 일이에요?
Why are you so beautiful?
왜 그렇게 아름다워요?
It would be a pity even if I granted you the title of Zhongdian
너에게 중전이라는 칭호를 준다고 해도 아쉽겠다.
What?
무엇?
Damn it, hey
젠장, 헤이
you are so beautiful
당신은 너무 아름다워요
What do you want me to do?
내가 무엇을 하기를 바라나요?
Mother
어머니
Come out immediately
즉시 나오세요
Don't even think about breaking off the engagement, don't even say anything.
약혼을 끊을 생각도 하지 말고, 아무 말도 하지 마세요.
Let me also live a life of power
나도 권력 있는 삶을 살게 하소서
As a concubine of a powerful minister's family
유력 장관 가문의 첩으로
With a 70-year-old man who doesn’t know when he will die?
언제 죽을지 모르는 70대 노인과?
My life has changed for the better
내 인생은 더 나은 쪽으로 바뀌었어요
He might lie somewhere and die without saying a word.
그는 아무 말도 하지 못한 채 어딘가에 누워 죽을 수도 있다.
I don't even need to cater to him
난 그 사람을 대접할 필요조차 없어
There is no need to observe words and expressions
단어나 표현을 관찰할 필요는 없습니다.
What happens after that?
그 후에는 어떻게 되나요?
You plan to be a widow for the rest of your life
평생 과부로 살 계획이신가요?
Have you never experienced love even once?
단 한 번도 사랑을 경험해 본 적이 없나요?
So what
그래서 뭐
Can that be eaten?
그거 먹어도 되나요?
Can I get a house in exchange?
교환으로 집을 구할 수 있나요?
It just makes people upset for no reason.
이유 없이 사람을 화나게 만들 뿐이죠.
My heart is churning
내 마음이 흔들리고 있어요
Feeling depressed all day long, feeling flustered and feeling like vomiting
하루종일 우울하고, 어지럽고, 토할 것 같은 느낌
I hate that. I don't want it.
나는 그것을 싫어한다. 나는 그것을 원하지 않습니다.
shut up
닥쳐
The Superintendent also...
소장님도..
No, I don't agree
아니요, 동의하지 않습니다.
Call off this marriage immediately
이 결혼을 즉시 취소하세요
What about after regretting the marriage?
결혼을 후회한 후에는 어떻습니까?
Want us kicked out of this room
우리가 이 방에서 쫓겨났으면 좋겠어
And then sleep on the street?
그러다 길거리에서 자나요?
Then who will suffer next?
그렇다면 다음 피해는 누구에게 있을까요?
Is it my sick mother?
아픈 엄마인가요?
Still young master
아직 어린 스승님
You want me to struggle alone in the quagmire again
넌 내가 또 수렁에서 혼자 애쓰길 원해
Don't you think it's too cruel?
너무 잔인하다고 생각하지 않나요?
I will relax and leave
나는 긴장을 풀고 떠날 것이다
it's my fault
그건 내 잘못이야
It's all my fault
다 내 잘못이야
sorry
미안
Eunjo, I'm sorry
은조야, 미안해
I'm sorry too
나도 미안해
Enzu
엔즈
Why did you come to my house?
우리 집에는 왜 왔나요?
Sorry, you are a lady who has not yet left the government.
죄송합니다. 당신은 아직 정부를 떠나지 않은 여성입니다.
I, a strange man, call you out casually
이상한 남자가 무심코 널 불러
Come first
먼저 오세요
Since you are my fiancé
당신은 내 약혼자니까
He's not a strange man either
그 사람도 이상한 사람은 아니잖아
You will soon regard me as a strange man
너는 곧 나를 이상한 사람으로 여기게 될 것이다.
Because we will break off the engagement
왜냐면 우리는 약혼을 파기할 것이기 때문이다
I don't understand what you are saying
무슨 말인지 이해가 안 돼요
Reason for breaking off the engagement...
약혼 파기 이유..
Refuse to be a sowing stallion
씨를 뿌리는 종마가 되기를 거부하라
Can you keep your self-esteem?
자존감을 지킬 수 있나요?
The reason is... The name I gave you
그 이유는... 내가 지어준 이름
wealth and fame
부와 명성
You are the same...
너도 똑같아...
Can't give up
포기할 수 없어
That's the real you
그게 진짜 너야
Despicable bastard
비열한 놈
If you can't let go of your friendship with that prostitute Lu Yi
그 매춘부 루이와의 우정을 놓을 수 없다면
Then I don't care
그럼 난 상관없어
If you keep insisting that you don’t care
계속 관심 없다고 주장한다면
At that time, I’m afraid it will really show its ugly face.
그때는 정말 추악한 모습을 보여주지 않을까 두렵습니다.
The bride must take the initiative to terminate the engagement
신부가 주도적으로 약혼을 종료해야 합니다.
It will not cause any trouble to you in the future
앞으로는 당신에게 문제를 일으키지 않을 것입니다.
please stay
머물러 주세요
You didn't hesitate to come in the rain
넌 비를 맞으면서도 주저하지 않고 왔어
Are you really determined to solve it as soon as possible?
가능한 한 빨리 문제를 해결하겠다고 정말로 결심하셨나요?
Just think of it as me struggling.
그냥 내가 고생하고 있다고 생각해주세요.
It's raining harder again
비가 또 더 세게 내리고 있어
It's almost time to leave
이제 떠날 시간이 거의 다 됐어요
Good
좋음
what is this
이게 뭐야?
Those are embroidered shoes
수놓은 신발이에요
I told you that it would get stained by muddy water, so I won’t wear embroidered shoes.
흙탕물에 젖을까봐 자수신발은 신지 않겠다고 하더군요.
These are not my embroidered shoes
이건 내가 수 놓은 신발이 아니야
That was what a young man put up together with the embroidered shoes just now.
방금 한 청년이 수놓은 구두와 함께 만들어 놓은 것이 바로 그것이었다.
It seems that I am worried that you will get married wearing wet shoes.
젖은 신발을 신고 결혼하게 될까 봐 걱정이 되는 것 같아요.
Could it be...
그럴 수도 있지...
when the raindrops fall on you
빗방울이 너에게 떨어지면
The depression in my heart seems to be diluted a little.
마음속의 우울함이 조금은 희석되는 것 같습니다.
How is it possible
어떻게 가능합니까?
I mean it
진심이야
Enzu, that kid knows it very well
엔즈, 그 아이는 그걸 아주 잘 알아
Lowly people don't deserve that kind of thing in the first place
낮은 사람들은 애초에 그런 일을 받을 자격이 없습니다
She must persist
그녀는 계속해야 해
what are you doing
뭐하는거야?
what is this doing
이게 뭐하는 거야?
I'm going to treat you like an animal
나는 당신을 동물처럼 대할 것입니다
How could you be so extravagant?
어떻게 그렇게 사치스러울 수 있나요?
Do you have to sell yourself?
자신을 팔아야합니까?
Master
마스터
The old man passed away
그 노인이 세상을 떠났어요
I'm an officer of the Bureau of Robbery
저는 강도국 직원입니다
Take me to see the prisoner
죄수를 만나러 데려가 주세요
What happened? What happened?
무슨 일이 일어났나요? 무슨 일이에요?
Call the other officers
다른 직원들한테 전화해
Go quickly Yes
빨리 가세요 예
Ji Tong?
지통?
Sir
선생님
what is that
그게 뭐야?
It's liquor
술이에요
You look needy tonight
오늘 밤 당신은 궁핍해 보여요
Enzu
엔즈
Uncle Shi
시 삼촌
You haven't eaten anything all day, right?
하루종일 아무것도 안 드셨죠?
This is for you
이것은 당신을 위한 것입니다
come on
어서
How did you get in here?
여기 어떻게 들어왔나요?
How else could he get in? Of course he was sold.
그가 또 어떻게 들어갈 수 있었습니까? 물론 그는 팔렸습니다.
Aren’t we all the property of two classes of nobles?
우리 모두는 두 계급의 귀족의 재산이 아닙니까?
After the owner’s house was confiscated and his family was exterminated
주인의 집이 몰수되고 그 가족이 몰살된 후
All property confiscated
모든 재산이 압수됨
Yesterday, I was sold to this family again.
어제 나는 또 이 가족에게 팔렸습니다.
Master Da Si Jian will go to the place of exile soon, right?
Da Si Jian 선사님은 곧 유배지로 가실 것입니다. 그렇죠?
He is gone now
그는 이제 사라졌습니다
Did he pass away? How could it be so sudden?
그가 세상을 떠났나요? 어떻게 그렇게 갑작스러울 수 있지?
I'm also surprised
나도 놀랐다
But what’s even more surprising is the news coming from the market
그런데 더욱 놀라운 것은 시장에서 들려오는 소식이다.
What's the news?
무슨 소식이 있나요?
It is said that my father was killed by Ji Tong
아버지가 지통에게 살해당했다고 합니다
What is Ji Tong?
지통이란 무엇입니까?
What do you mean Ji Tong killed someone?
Ji Tong이 누군가를 죽였다는 게 무슨 뜻인가요?
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
Anyway, no one will enter the other courtyard tonight.
어쨌든, 오늘 밤에는 아무도 다른 안뜰로 들어가지 못할 것입니다.
Are you hunting for Ji Dong?
지동을 찾고 있나요?
Already investigating
이미 조사 중
What else to investigate?
또 무엇을 조사해야 할까요?
On my master’s blood book
내 주인의 피의 책에
They all wrote the name Jitong
그들은 모두 Jitong이라는 이름을 썼습니다.
A blood letter?
혈액 편지?
Does that mean he left a last message?
그 사람이 마지막 메시지를 남겼다는 뜻인가요?
before having clear evidence
확실한 증거가 나오기 전에
Please wait a little longer
조금만 더 기다려주세요
No evidence was found
증거가 발견되지 않았습니다
Go to the Robbery Hall
강도회관으로 가세요
Let's go Yes
가자 응
It's Ji Tong
지통이에요
Ji Tong appears
지통이 등장
Ji Tong? Did someone call Ji Tong just now?
지통? 지금 누군가 Ji Tong에게 전화했나요?
that way
그런 식으로
You have to get up
일어나야 해
How long have I been in coma?
내가 혼수상태에 있었던 지 얼마나 됐나요?
Wine table?
와인 테이블?
I was clearly being chased by patrol officers and soldiers just now.
나는 지금 분명히 순찰대원과 군인들에게 쫓기고 있는 것이 분명했습니다.
What's going on with this satin? Wait a minute.
이 새틴에 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요? 잠깐 기다려요.
How did my hands become like this?
내 손이 어쩌다 이렇게 됐지?
Why is my head so dizzy?
머리가 왜 이렇게 어지러워?
What's going on
무슨 일이야?
why am i on the street
내가 왜 길거리에 있지?
Ji Tong appears
지통이 등장
Catch Ji Tong quickly
빨리 지통을 잡아라
Ji Tong?
지통?
What's going on
무슨 일이야?
This face…
이 얼굴은…
Are you an official?
당신은 공무원입니까?
Is anyone here?
여기 누구 있어요?
Did we really exchange souls?
우리 정말 영혼을 교환한 걸까?
In the palace? Is this in the palace?
궁전에서요? 여기가 궁전에 있나요?
Is this a dream?
이게 꿈인가요?
Because this is my home from yesterday
여기가 어제부터 내 집이니까
It seems that there was a dispute between the couple last night
어젯밤에 부부간에 말다툼이 있었던 것 같습니다
who is your husband
당신의 남편은 누구입니까?
what makes me angry is
나를 화나게 하는 것은
I'm so useless that I even gave you embroidered shoes.
나는 너무 쓸모없어서 너에게 수 놓은 신발까지 줬어.
Since none of the adults got up, I came in to take a look.
어른들은 아무도 안 일어나서 구경하러 들어갔어요.
But the person is no longer inside
하지만 그 사람은 더 이상 안에 있지 않아요
What does it mean that Ji Tong was arrested?
Ji Tong이 체포되었다는 것은 무엇을 의미합니까?
Go find an adult immediately
당장 어른을 찾아보세요